Guide to the William Winlock Miller Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
William Winlock Miller collection
1845-1958
WA MSS S-1172
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
4.25
(11 boxes)
The collection consists primarily of the papers of W. W. Miller, but it also includes the correspondence and writings of many northwestern pioneers. The papers document the organization and development of Washington Territory, and in particular, political affairs and local governement administration. Along with Miller's personal, business, and government papers, there are letters to Gov. Isaac Stevens and his writings. There are also photographs and financial, legal, and biographical material on northwestern pioneers.
Miller, William Winlock, 1822-1876
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Winlock William Miller (Y1984), 1953.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Associated Materials
William Winlock Miller Papers. WA MSS S-119
Scope and Contents
The William Winlock Miller Collection consists primarily of the papers of William Winlock Miller (d. 1876), but also includes papers from other Pacific Northwest pioneers, including Governor Isaac I. Stevens, and Elwood Evans. The collection supplements material in the William Winlock Miller Papers, Western Americana Manuscript S-119. Additional manuscripts about the history of the Pacific Northwest, collected by the Miller family and given to Yale, are described in A Catalogue of Manuscripts in the Collection of Western Americana, compiled by Mary C. Withington.
Miller began his career as a teacher in Illinois. From there he moved to Oregon Territory in 1849, on account of his health. After a period of teaching, he took over the accounts of M. T. Simmons, a storekeeper in Tum Water and one of the first settlers in what later became Washington Territory. Miller took his first government position in 1851, as the first Surveyor and Inspector of Revenue for the Port of Nisqually. He had many dealings with the Hudson Bay Company, and with W. F. Tolmie, head of the Puget Sound Agricultural Company. Miller was a friend and supporter of Isaac I. Stevens, the first Governor of Washington Territory, and later administered Stevens' estate. Miller held many official positions during his life, including Quarter Master General of the Washington Territory Militia during the Indian hostilities, 1857-61; Director and Commissioner for Olympia of the North Pacific Railroad Company, 1857; Notary Public in the District Court, 1857, 1861; Treasurer for the Territory Fund for the Relief of Sick and Disabled Soldiers, 1862; and Mayor of Olympia, 1872. In 1861 he was appointed Superintendent of Indian Affairs for Washington Territory, a position for which his supporters had been recommending him to President Buchanan since 1857. Miller's private business affairs included a partnership in a sawmill, 1853, business as a cattle-broker, 1862-63; and shareholdings in a woolen factory, 1864. He was also a Master Mason of Olympia Lodge No. 1.
This collection gives much information about the organization and development of Washington Territory, with particular emphasis on political affairs and the administration of local government units. The collection is divided into three series: W. W. Miller, I. I. Stevens and Special Files.
The W. W. Miller series is divided into two subseries: Correspondence and Papers. Correspondence consists mainly of letters received by Miller from friends and business associates, many of whom he knew in both capacities. This section also includes a number of letters written by Miller, most of which are his own retained file copies. The letters discuss personal affairs, contain requests for help in acquiring positions, and discussions of the political affairs in the Territory. Notable correspondents include Governor Isaac I. Stevens and his family, Obadiah B. McFadden, Territorial Supreme Court Judge and W. W. Miller's father-in-law, and several of the Territorial Governors and officials. Of particular interest is a letter from Stevens' widow describing the Governor's death in battle (September 12, 1862); Miller's letter to George Gibbs about the purchase of Alaska (September 2, 1867); and correspondence with Robert Miller (November 14, 1858) about Joseph Winlock, Miller's cousin, who was killed by the Indians. (See also Series III, for Winlock W. Miller, Jr.'s compilation of pioneer reminiscences on the same subject.)
The Papers subseries includes letters of appointment, some of which are Presidential, accounts and business papers connected with Miller's official positions, agreements pertaining to his private business affairs, and numerous receipts. A large proportion of the material in this section are financial papers.
The I. I. Stevens series contains material relating to Isaac Ingalls Stevens (1818-62), who became the first Governor of the newly separated Washington Territory in 1853, and was also appointed director of the survey of a northern route for a Pacific Railroad. In 1856, during Indian hostilities, he proclaimed martial law in Pierce and Thurston counties, as a result of which he was later arrested for contempt of court. For further biographical information, see "The Life of Isaac Ingalls Stevens" by his son, Hazard Stevens (1900). The series is divided into two subseries: Correspondence and Writings. The letters in the Correspondence subseries are principally those received by Stevens, and are mainly concerned with political matters. The most notable correspondent is W. W. Miller. The Writings section contains an article and notes, some resolutions about the Indian war and communications in Washington Territory, and a draft of Stevens' will.
Special Files contains papers--including correspondence and manuscripts--of persons other than W. W. Miller and I. I. Stevens, relating to the activities of Miller and Stevens, as well as to the Washington Territory and the early history of the Pacific Northwest. The series is divided into three subseries: Correspondence, Writings, and Subjects.
The Correspondence subseries contains correspondence among many of Washington Territory's well known pioneers, including Elwood Evans, who took part in Governor Stevens' Northern Pacific Railroad exploration and survey and was Secretary of Washington Territory; T. F. McElroy, founder of Olympia's first newspaper; O. B. McFadden; Mrs. Mary M. Miller, Miller's widow; Winlock W. Miller, Sr., Miller's son, and W. F. Tolmie. There is a large section consisting of the correspondence of Henry G. Struve, also a Secretary of Washington Territory, mainly letters from Struve to his wife, who appears to have been a friend of Mrs. Miller's. Of particular interest is a note from Abraham Lincoln recommending W. W. Miller to the Post Master General (February 23, 1864) published in Collected Works of Abraham Lincoln, (ed.) Roy P. Basler, 1953.
The Writings section contains addresses, articles, notes and poems by several writers. Of particular interest are the writings of Elwood Evans which pertain to the history of Northwest America and to the Indians; poems by Francis Henry about pioneers in Washington; and writings by Winlock W. Miller, Jr., Miller's grandson, about W. W. Miller and Joseph Winlock.
The Subjects section contains a variety of materials, including biographical and historical information, mainly in the form of newspaper clippings, and various financial papers, legal documents, and photographs. Of particular interest are those documents relating to land sales by Edmund Sylvester, the "founder" of Olympia, on whose original land claim the city was built; documents relating to the formation of the Puget Sound Steamship Company, and a notebook and papers relating to a secret society, the U.F.F.U.
For further material pertaining to Elwood Evans, O. B. McFadden, Isaac I. Stevens, W. F. Tolmie, William W. Miller and Winlock W. Miller, Jr., see the index to A Catalogue of Manuscripts in the Collection of Western Americana, compiled by Mary C. Withington.
A complete chronological list of all the correspondence in the Collection is shelved in the office of the curator of the Western Americana Collection.
Indians of North America -- Washington (State); Yakama Indians -- Wars, 1855-1859; Washington (State) -- History; Washington (State) -- Politics and government; Public officers -- Washington (State); Evans, Elwood, 1828-1898; Gibbs, George, 1815-1873; Henry, Francis, 1827-1893; McElroy, T. F.; McFadden, Obadiah B., 1817-1875; Miller, Mary M.; Miller, Robert, fl. 1858; Miller, William Winlock, Jr.; Miller, William Winlock, 1822-1876; Miller, William Winlock, 1822-1876; Stevens, Isaac Ingalls, 1818-1862; Struve, Henry G.; Swan, James G., 1818-1900; Tolmie, William Fraser, 1812-1886; Winlock, Joseph, 1826-1875
- W. W. Miller, 1845-83; Series I; (7 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  The series is divided into two subseries: Correspondence and Papers. The Correspondence subseries contains letters received by W. W. Miller, arranged alphabetically by the name of the writer of the letter. Letters are arranged chronologically within each folder. Letters written by Miller (with the exception of those he wrote to I. I. Stevens, which appear in Series II) are arranged alphabetically by the name of the person to whom the letter was addressed, and chronologically within each folder. The Papers subseries is arranged alphabetically by category, and chronologically within each category.
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Incoming letters
      - Abernethy, Alexander, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Adair, John, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Ahern, P., 1861 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Aiken, Fred A., 1860 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Anderson, J. Patton, 1855-57 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Anderson, J. W., 1861 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Ankers ?, J., 1853 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Armstrong, C. H., 1866-74, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Ball, J. L., 1874 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Ball, W. A., 1867 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Bancroft, A. A., 1861 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Barker, S., 1860 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Beale, T. W., 1861 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Bellman, B., 1864 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Bellows, H. W., 1863 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Bennington, W. S., 1861 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Berkey, Peter, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Berry, H. W., 1865 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Biddle, B. R., 1854, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Bigelow, D. R., 1852-65 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Biles, J. D., 1854, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Blinn, M., 1862 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Bradford, David F., 1861 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Bradley, Henry, 1859, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Bradly, Charles, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Breshears, J. S., 1868 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Briscoe, John, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Brooks, Quincy A., 1853-65 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Brotchie, Capt. W., 1853 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Brown, H. H., 1872 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Brown, Samuel, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Bryant, H. P. O, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - [Buckelner?], James M., 1854 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - Burbank, A. R., 1860-64 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Burr, Henry, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - Butler, H., 1859 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - Cain, A. J., 1856-57 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      - Cain, A. J., 1860-74, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - Cain, John, 1856-64 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      - Calhoun, G. O., 1872 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      - Campbell, H., 1859 (Box 1, Folder 41)
      - Campbell, Harriet B., 1870 (Box 1, Folder 42)
      - Campner ?, A., 1853 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      - Canfield, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 44)
      - Cannady, J. M., 1860-67 (Box 1, Folder 45)
      - Capers, H. L., 1872 (Box 1, Folder 46)
      - Carlton, W. H., 1858 (Box 1, Folder 47)
      - Catlin, John, 1857-70 (Box 1, Folder 48)
      - Catlin, Seth, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 49)
      - Chambers, T. M., 1861 (Box 1, Folder 50)
      - Chapman, A. J., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 51)
      - Chase, H. M., 1874 (Box 1, Folder 52)
      - Chenoweth, F. A., 1860 (Box 1, Folder 53)
      - Clark, Frank, 1861-72 (Box 1, Folder 54)
      - Clarke, Fred A., 1863-72 (Box 1, Folder 55)
      - Clarke, George, 1867 (Box 1, Folder 56)
      - Clendenin, J. S., 1855 (Box 1, Folder 57)
      - Coal Creek Road Co., 1867 (Box 1, Folder 58)
      - Cocke, John S., 1867 (Box 1, Folder 59)
      - Cole, G. E., 1866 (Box 1, Folder 60)
      - Cole, J. N., 1872 (Box 1, Folder 61)
      - Conklin, William G., 1872 (Box 1, Folder 62)
      - Conser, J., 1852 (Box 1, Folder 63)
      - Coombs, S. F., 1872 (Box 1, Folder 64)
      - Coonty (?), John A., 1871 (Box 1, Folder 65)
      - Corliss, G. W., 1857 (Box 1, Folder 66)
      - Coulter, S., 1870 (Box 1, Folder 67)
      - Crosbie, Henry R., 1854-70 (Box 1, Folder 68)
      - Curtis, S. B., 1857-61 (Box 1, Folder 69)
      - Cushing, Caleb, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      - Cushman, Joseph, 1861-68, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 71)
      - Travers, Daniel, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 72)
      - Dennison, B. F., 1860 (Box 1, Folder 73)
      - Denny, A. A., 1860-72 (Box 1, Folder 74)
      - Department of Interior [Acting Secretary J. Campman, Secretary R. McClelland], 1855-57 (Box 1, Folder 75)
      - Department of Interior [Secretary J. Thompson], 1857-60 (Box 2, Folder 76)
      - Department of Interior [W. P. Dole], 1864 (Box 2, Folder 77)
      - Dickerson, J. B., 1860 (Box 2, Folder 78)
      - District Court, Jefferson County [Simon Bussassa], 1854 (Box 2, Folder 79)
      - Dodge, D., 1860 (Box 2, Folder 80)
      - Douglas, J., 1851 (Box 2, Folder 81)
      - Doyle, R. L., 1853 (Box 2, Folder 82)
      - Dryer, T. J., 1852 (Box 2, Folder 83)
      - DuBeau, L. L., 1872 (Box 2, Folder 84)
      - Duke, B. F., 1862 (Box 2, Folder 85)
      - Durgin, S. D., 1859-67 (Box 2, Folder 86)
      - Eastman, C. A., 1861, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 87)
      - Ebey, I. N., 1853-[55?] (Box 2, Folder 88)
      - Ebey [?], W. S., 1855 (Box 2, Folder 89)
      - Ensign, Lewis, 1856 (Box 2, Folder 90)
      - Evans, Elwood, 1855 (Box 2, Folder 91)
      - Failings & Nott, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 92)
      - Fairchield, W., 1859 (Box 2, Folder 93)
      - Fales, D. R., 1859 (Box 2, Folder 94)
      - Fargo, S. B., 1862 (Box 2, Folder 95)
      - Felton, C. C., 1860 (Box 2, Folder 96)
      - Fennebaker, J. A., 1862 (Box 2, Folder 97)
      - Files, J. C., 1857, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 98)
      - Finch, D. R., 1865 (Box 2, Folder 99)
      - First National Bank of Portland [H. Failing, President], 1871 (Box 2, Folder 100)
      - Fisher, A. D., 1859 (Box 2, Folder 101)
      - Fitzhugh, 1856-60 (Box 2, Folder 102)
      - Flanders, A., 1868 (Box 2, Folder 103)
      - Fletcher, Thomas J., 1859-69 (Box 2, Folder 104)
      - Ford, G., 1862 (Box 2, Folder 105)
      - Fowler, E. S., 1858 (Box 2, Folder 106)
      - Fowley, William, 1875 (Box 2, Folder 107)
      - Francis, Allen, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 108)
      - Frost, M. H., 1857-74 (Box 2, Folder 109)
      - Furste, Edward, 1856-62 (Box 2, Folder 110)
      - Furste, F. L., 1861 (Box 2, Folder 111)
      - Galbreath, James, 1860 (Box 2, Folder 112)
      - Garfield, S., 1869-72 (Box 2, Folder 113)
      - Gatson, B.?, 1853 (Box 2, Folder 114)
      - Geary, Edward R., 1860, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 115)
      - Gibbs, George, 1854-70 (Box 2, Folder 116)
      - Gilliam, W. S., 1862 (Box 2, Folder 117)
      - Glasgow, T. W., 1860-63 (Box 2, Folder 118)
      - Goldsborough, Hugh A., 1856-65 (Box 2, Folder 119)
      - Goodell, I. W., 1856 (Box 2, Folder 120)
      - Gosnell, W. B., 1860-68 (Box 2, Folder 121)
      - Greenwell, S. W., 1860 (Box 2, Folder 122)
      - Griswold, M. S., 1862, 1869 (Box 2, Folder 123)
      - Griswold, W. C., 1862 (Box 2, Folder 124)
      - Grover, L. F., 1857 (Box 2, Folder 125)
      - Hall, Washington, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 126)
      - Harding, B. F., 1864 (Box 2, Folder 127)
      - Harnedy, B., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 128)
      - Hathorn, Dennis, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 129)
      - Hayden, Gary, 1872 (Box 2, Folder 130)
      - Henness, B. L., 1861 (Box 2, Folder 131)
      - Henry (?), 1854 (Box 2, Folder 132)
      - Henry, A. G., 1862-65 (Box 2, Folder 133)
      - Hewitt, C. C., 1867 (Box 2, Folder 134)
      - Hicks, Urban E., 1860 (Box 2, Folder 135)
      - Holmes, Leander, 1863, 1866 (Box 2, Folder 136)
      - Horn ?, Jacob, n.y. (Box 2, Folder 137)
      - Howe, S. D., 1868 (Box 2, Folder 138)
      - Hubbard, D. J., 1863 (Box 2, Folder 139)
      - Hubbs, Charles H., 1861, 1867 (Box 2, Folder 140)
      - Hubbe, Paul K., 1860-62 (Box 2, Folder 141)
      - Huggins, Edward, 1853-66 (Box 2, Folder 142)
      - Hughes, George, 1873 (Box 2, Folder 143)
      - Humason & Curry, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 144)
      - Hurd, J. S., 1857, 1859 (Box 2, Folder 145)
      - Ingalls, George, 1854 (Box 2, Folder 146)
      - Ingalls, Rufus, 1858, 1859 (Box 2, Folder 147)
      - Jackson, John R., 1860 (Box 2, Folder 148)
      - Jaquith, J. S., 1857-61 (Box 2, Folder 149)
      - Johnson, George L., 1864, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 150)
      - Johnson, Jasper William, 1859-60 (Box 2, Folder 151)
      - Johnson, W. C., 1866 (Box 2, Folder 152)
      - Johnston, John, 1853 (Box 3, Folder 153)
      - Judson, H. A., 1859 (Box 3, Folder 154)
      - Judson, John P., 1872-74 (Box 3, Folder 155)
      - Kearney, E., 1871 (Box 3, Folder 156)
      - Kelly, William, 1857-62 (Box 3, Folder 157)
      - Kendull, B. F., 1856 (Box 3, Folder 158)
      - Kennedy, James K., 1867 (Box 3, Folder 159)
      - King, Thomas Starr, 1862 (Box 3, Folder 160)
      - Knox, John T., 1862-72 (Box 3, Folder 161)
      - Lackwood, William, 1852 (Box 3, Folder 162)
      - de Lacy, Walter W., 1874 (Box 3, Folder 163)
      - Ladd & Tilton, 1861-70 (Box 3, Folder 164)
      - Ladu, C., 1859-60 (Box 3, Folder 165)
      - Ladu, James B., 1859, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 166)
      - Lander, Edward, 1854-68 (Box 3, Folder 167)
      - Lander, S. F., 1853 (Box 3, Folder 168)
      - Lane, Joseph, 1852, 1859 (Box 3, Folder 169)
      - Lane, Richard, 1860 (Box 3, Folder 170)
      - Lansdale, R. H., 1853-60 (Box 3, Folder 171)
      - Latham, John, 1871 (Box 3, Folder 172)
      - Lightner, Isaac, 1861, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 173)
      - Lodge, James, 1860 (Box 3, Folder 174)
      - Logan, David, 1852, 1857 (Box 3, Folder 175)
      - Looney, James C., 1853 (Box 3, Folder 176)
      - Looney, John B., 1852-58 (Box 3, Folder 177)
      - Lord, D. R., 1867 (Box 3, Folder 178)
      - Lowe, Thomas G., 1868 (Box 3, Folder 179)
      - Lowell, A. C., 1856 (Box 3, Folder 180)
      - Lucas, Josiah M., 1852-71 (Box 3, Folder 181)
      - Lucas, Miss Mary J., 1856, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 182)
      - McCarven, M. M., 1869 (Box 3, Folder 183)
      - McDonald, J. S., 1866 (Box 3, Folder 184)
      - McElroy, 1863-68, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 185)
      - McFadden, O. B., 1858-66 (Box 3, Folder 186)
      - McFadden, O. B., 1867-73 (Box 3, Folder 187)
      - McFadden, O. B., 1874-75, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 188)
      - McGill, Henry M., 1860, 1867 (Box 3, Folder 189)
      - McGilvra, John J., 1867 (Box 3, Folder 190)
      - McHahon, 1854 (Box 3, Folder 191)
      - McLaw & Co., S., 1861 (Box 3, Folder 192)
      - McMullen, Gov. Fayette, 1857-58 (Box 3, Folder 193)
      - McPherson, Jhon, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 194)
      - Mahony, Frank, 1856 (Box 3, Folder 195)
      - Marsh, E., 1860-68 (Box 3, Folder 196)
      - Martin, Abner, 1855 (Box 3, Folder 197)
      - Mason, C. H., 1852, 1858 (Box 3, Folder 198)
      - Massey, E. S., 1860 (Box 3, Folder 199)
      - Matthias, Franklin, 1856-75 (Box 3, Folder 200)
      - Maxon, 1859-61 (Box 3, Folder 201)
      - May, Samuel E., 1857 (Box 3, Folder 202)
      - Meek, Joseph L., 1852 (Box 3, Folder 203)
      - Miles, Henry, 1859 (Box 3, Folder 204)
      - Millard, M. B., [1856?], 1857 (Box 3, Folder 205)
      - Miller, E. T. (brother), 1858 (Box 3, Folder 206)
      - Mitchell, W. A., 1867-75 (Box 3, Folder 207)
      - Monat, W. A., 1853 (?) (Box 3, Folder 208)
      - Morgan, H. D., 1861 (Box 3, Folder 209)
      - Morrow, I. J., 1859, 1860 (Box 3, Folder 210)
      - Morrow, William M., 1859-63 (Box 3, Folder 211)
      - Moses, A. Benton, 1853, 1854 (Box 3, Folder 212)
      - Moses, Simpson P., 1852 (Box 3, Folder 213)
      - Mullan, John, 1861, 1867 (Box 3, Folder 214)
      - Nathorn, Dennis, 1861 (Box 3, Folder 215)
      - Nelson, H. C., 1852 (Box 3, Folder 216)
      - Nesmith, J. W., 1866 (Box 4, Folder 217)
      - Newman, W. B. D., 1856 (Box 4, Folder 218)
      - Nolte, J. F., 1852 (Box 4, Folder 219)
      - Office of the Commission on Indian War Expenses in Oregon and Washington Territories [J. R. Daniel], 1857 (Box 4, Folder 220)
      - Offutt, James W., 1867-70, n.y. (Box 4, Folder 221)
      - O'Harven, W. F., 1859-61 (Box 4, Folder 222)
      - Owens, John, 1858-71 (Box 4, Folder 223)
      - Packard, J. A., 1861 (Box 4, Folder 224)
      - Pagett, C. C., 1857-73 (Box 4, Folder 225)
      - Paige, George A., 1859-64 (Box 4, Folder 226)
      - Parkwood, W., 1860 (Box 4, Folder 227)
      - Patterson, [Ira?], 1860 (Box 4, Folder 228)
      - Patton, T. M. F., 1857 (Box 4, Folder 229)
      - Peabody, R. V., 1858-62 (Box 4, Folder 230)
      - Perkins, A. A., 1872 (Box 4, Folder 231)
      - Phillip, Charley, Indian, 1873 (Box 4, Folder 232)
      - Phillips, Horton and Co., 1871 (Box 4, Folder 233)
      - Phillips, C. C., 1860 (Box 4, Folder 234)
      - Phillips, David, 1866-73 (Box 4, Folder 235)
      - Phinn & Nevills, 1860 (Box 4, Folder 236)
      - Phinney, Amos & Co. [A. B. Patrick], 1862 (Box 4, Folder 237)
      - Pickering, Gov. William, 1864-65 (Box 4, Folder 238)
      - Pinto, H. H., 1861 (Box 4, Folder 239)
      - Poe, A., 1853-59, n.y. (Box 4, Folder 240)
      - Potts, Richard, 1855 (Box 4, Folder 241)
      - Powe, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 242)
      - Prather, Thomas, 1857, 1873 (Box 4, Folder 243)
      - Reed, J. M, 1870 (Box 4, Folder 244)
      - Renton, W., 1862 (Box 4, Folder 245)
      - Ritz, Philip, 1875 (Box 4, Folder 246)
      - Robbins, G. Collier, 1862 (Box 4, Folder 247)
      - Roberts, George B., 1858, 1861 (Box 4, Folder 248)
      - Roberts, L. H., 1860, 1861 (Box 4, Folder 249)
      - Robie, A. H., 1857-59 (Box 4, Folder 250)
      - Roeders, H., 1861-72 (Box 4, Folder 251)
      - Ross, George, Jr., 1852, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 252)
      - Ruth, B. F., 1866 (Box 4, Folder 253)
      - Rutledge, W. M., 1862 (Box 4, Folder 254)
      - Sayward, W. S., 1858 (Box 4, Folder 255)
      - Scott, John T., 1861 (Box 4, Folder 256)
      - "76", 1858 (Box 4, Folder 257)
      - Sewell, John, 1859 (Box 4, Folder 258)
      - Shang, C. W., 1858 (Box 4, Folder 259)
      - Shaw, B. F. (Frank Shaw), 1856-62 (Box 4, Folder 260)
      - Shaw, B. F. (Frank Shaw), 1863-70, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 261)
      - Shelton, David, 1858 (Box 4, Folder 262)
      - Simmons, A. H., 1860-67 (Box 4, Folder 263)
      - Simmons, William M., 1873 (Box 4, Folder 264)
      - Slaughter, W. A., (1853?) (Box 4, Folder 265)
      - Smith & Davis, 1861 (Box 4, Folder 266)
      - Smith, A. C., 1860 (Box 4, Folder 267)
      - Smith, G. T., 1871 (Box 4, Folder 268)
      - Smith, Isaac W., 1868-72 (Box 4, Folder 269)
      - Smith, Sam D., 1865-72 (Box 4, Folder 270)
      - Smith, Victor, 1862-64 (Box 4, Folder 271)
      - Staines, R. J., 1854 (Box 4, Folder 272)
      - Starling, E. A., 1852-53 (Box 4, Folder 273)
      - Starr, A. M. & L. M., 1861 (Box 4, Folder 274)
      - Steiwer, F., 1852-54 (Box 4, Folder 275)
      - Stevens, Hazard, 1864-70 (Box 4, Folder 276)
      - Stevens, Henry K., 1859-61 (Box 4, Folder 277)
      - Stevens, Isaac I., 1853-58 (Box 4, Folder 278)
      - Stevens, Isaac I., 1858 (Box 4, Folder 279)
      - Stevens, Isaac I., 1859 (Box 4, Folder 280)
      - Stevens, Isaac I., 1860 (Box 5, Folder 281)